<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Tutorial02</string>

    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="CS">Al-Khwarizmi popularizing treatise on algebra (The Compendious Book on Calculation by Completion
        and Balancing, c. 813–833 CE[9]:171) presented the first systematic solution of linear and quadratic equations.
        One of his principal achievements in algebra was his demonstration of how to solve quadratic equations by
        completing the square, for which he provided geometric justifications.[8]:14 Because he was the first to treat
        algebra as an independent discipline and introduced the methods of "reduction" and "balancing" (the
        transposition of subtracted terms to the other side of an equation, that is, the cancellation of like terms on
        opposite sides of the equation),[10] he has been described as the father[11][12] or founder[13][14] of algebra.
    </string>
    <string name="ECE">"Attempting to develop inventions he could patent and market, Tesla conducted a range of
        experiments with mechanical oscillators/generators, electrical discharge tubes, and early X-ray imaging. He also
        built a wireless-controlled boat, one of the first ever exhibited. Tesla became well known as an inventor and
        would demonstrate his achievements to celebrities and wealthy patrons at his lab, and was noted for his
        showmanship at public lectures. Throughout the 1890s, Tesla pursued his ideas for wireless lighting and
        worldwide wireless electric power distribution in his high-voltage, high-frequency power experiments in New York
        and Colorado Springs. In 1893, he made pronouncements on the possibility of wireless communication with his
        devices. Tesla tried to put these ideas to practical use in his unfinished Wardenclyffe Tower project, an
        intercontinental wireless communication and power transmitter, but ran out of funding before he could complete
        it.[7]
    </string>
    <string name="MATH">In Principia, Newton formulated the laws of motion and universal gravitation that formed the
        dominant scientific viewpoint until it was superseded by the theory of relativity. Newton used his mathematical
        description of gravity to prove Kepler laws of planetary motion, account for tides, the trajectories of comets,
        the precession of the equinoxes and other phenomena, eradicating doubt about the Solar System heliocentricity.
        He demonstrated that the motion of objects on Earth and celestial bodies could be accounted for by the same
        principles. Newton inference that the Earth is an oblate spheroid was later confirmed by the geodetic
        measurements of Maupertuis, La Condamine, and others, convincing most European scientists of the superiority of
        Newtonian mechanics over earlier systems.
    </string>
    <string name="STAT">Gertrude Mary Cox (January 13, 1900 – October 17, 1978) was an American statistician and founder
        of the department of Experimental Statistics at North Carolina State University. She was later appointed
        director of both the Institute of Statistics of the Consolidated University of North Carolina and the Statistics
        Research Division of North Carolina State University. Her most important and influential research dealt with
        experimental design; she wrote an important book on the subject with W. G. Cochran. In 1949 Cox became the first
        female elected into the International Statistical Institute and in 1956 was President of the American
        Statistical Association.
    </string>
    <string name="PHYS">Newton built the first practical reflecting telescope and developed a sophisticated theory of
        colour based on the observation that a prism separates white light into the colours of the visible spectrum. His
        work on light was collected in his highly influential book Opticks, published in 1704. He also formulated an
        empirical law of cooling, made the first theoretical calculation of the speed of sound, and introduced the
        notion of a Newtonian fluid. In addition to his work on calculus, as a mathematician Newton contributed to the
        study of power series, generalised the binomial theorem to non-integer exponents, developed a method for
        approximating the roots of a function, and classified most of the cubic plane curves.
    </string>

    <string name="CSurl">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Muhammad_ibn_Musa_al-Khwarizmi</string>
    <string name="PHYSurl">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Isaac_Newton</string>
    <string name="STATurl">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gertrude_Mary_Cox</string>
    <string name="MATHurl">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Isaac_Newton</string>
    <string name="ECEurl">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nikola_Tesla</string>

</resources>
